Python is the most popular programming language in the world because of its simple and beginner-friendly syntax.
And that's the number one reason it's hated by C++ programmers.
It's the language of choice for artificial intelligence and machine learning,
but also heavily used in scripting, automation, and backend development.
It has a huge ecosystem of third-party libraries such as Numpi for numerical computing, pandas,
for data analysis, psychic learn, for machine learning, tensor flow, for deep learning,
Django, for building web applications, and Keevy for cross-platform, desktop, and mobile apps.
In case you care, Python is 33 years old. It was created by a Dutch programmer in 1991
and named after the British comedy Monty Python. Python is an interpreted language, meaning you can
run your code without the compilation step. But you need an interpreter that's written in C for
performance. Unlike other languages, Python has hidden gems. We can import this for the
zen of Python or anti-gravity for a fun surprise. We can declare a variable with a name and a value
that can be a string, a Boolean, or a number. Python is a dynamically typed language,
meaning the type of variables is determined at runtime. Unlike other languages in Python,
we can add or even multiply strings and numbers. Python has four types of collections, lists,
topples, sets, and dictionaries. Now, unlike many languages, we can use a negative index to count
backwards. To define a function, we use the dev keyword and indentation to declare a block of code,
so no curly braces. And that's another reason Python is hated by C++ programmers.
Python also supports object-oriented programming. We can define classes using the class keyword and
have them inherit from each other. Python comes with batteries included, a huge library of built-in
modules for tasks like working with CSV, JSON, emails, web scraping, and so on. And that was Python
in two minutes. Want to learn Python? Check out my tutorials.